<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hendrik Meyer-Ohle</title><link>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/</link><description>Recent content on Hendrik Meyer-Ohle</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024, Hendrik Meyer-Ohle</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.hmeyerohle.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Current Research</title><link>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/current_research/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/current_research/</guid><description>Current Research Organization of Human Resources Management of Japanese Firms
This project looks at the way that Japanese companies organize the human resources management function. What role does the human resources management department play in Japanese companies and is this role changing? What are the expectations towards people working in human resources management and is professionalization advancing? This project is being conducted in collaboration with Harald Conrad from Dusseldorf University.</description></item><item><title>Previous Research</title><link>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/previous_research/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/previous_research/</guid><description>Previous Research Shopping Centers as Places of Marketing and Consumption
The number of shopping centers has been increasing rapidly in Japan over the last decade with developers in an intensifying competition constantly testing the frontiers in terms of locations, size, or tenant mix. The development of shopping centers is taking place in a climate of an aging and shrinking population, economic uncertainties and increasing differentiation within Japanese society and between metropolitan centers and the rest of Japan.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hmeyerohle.me/about/</guid><description>Education 1994 (December) Dr phil Philipps University Marburg (Dissertation on innovation and dynamics in Japanese retailing) 1991/1992 Double degree in Business Administration (Diplom-Kaufmann) and Japanese Studies (Magister Artium) - Philipps University Marburg 1986 to 1992 Undergraduate Studies in Business Administration and Japanese Studies - Philipps University Marburg Employment National University of Singapore
December 2022 – Head Department of Japanese Studies January 2011 - June 2015 Head Department of Japanese Studies January 2009 - December 2010 Vice Dean Graduate Studies and International Relations - Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences January 2007 - December 2007 Acting Head Department of Japanese Studies August 2005 - December 2007 Assistant Dean Graduate Studies and Research Faculty of Arts and Social Sciences August 2005 - December 2006 Deputy Head Department of Japanese Studies July 2005 - Associate Professor Department of Japanese Studies January 2000 - 2005 Assistant Professor Department of Japanese Studies German Institute of Japanese Studies, (DIJ), Tokyo</description></item></channel></rss>